<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publications on Sancar Adali - personal website</title>
    <link>https://adalisan.github.io/publication/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publications on Sancar Adali - personal website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016 Sancar Adali</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/publication/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Seeded Graph Matching</title>
      <link>https://adalisan.github.io/publication/sgm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adalisan.github.io/publication/sgm/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fidelity-Commensurability Tradeoff in Joint Embedding of Disparate Dissimilarities</title>
      <link>https://adalisan.github.io/publication/fidcommjofc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adalisan.github.io/publication/fidcommjofc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s say our data does not consist of $n$ observations of $d$-dimensional vectors, but instead an $n \times n$ matrix, whose entries consist of the dissimilarities between the $n$ observations as measured by a bivariate function $\delta(.,.)$.  We refer to the computation of $n$ separate $d$-dimensional vectors/points  that is as consistent as possible with a dissimilarity matrices as &amp;ldquo;embedding&amp;rdquo; this dissimilarity matrix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider the embedding of $K$   dissimilarity(distance-like) matrices between $n$ objects (coming from $K$ different bivariate functions  $\delta_k(.,.)$ ) or observations of $n$  $K-tuples$ of similar objects. In any case the different dissimilarity matrices are related in a statistical or causal sense. We refer to this relation as &amp;ldquo;matched&amp;rdquo;. Say $K=2$. A joint  embedding of these dissimilarity matrices will result in $2n$ points that consist of $n$ matched points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To embed multiple dissimilarities  ${\Delta_k},k=1,2$  into a commensurate space, so that the information represented in different dissimality matrices can be used for a data exploitation task,  an omnibus dissimilarity matrix  $M \in \mathbb{R}^{nk \times nk}$  is constructed. Consider, for $K=2$,
$$
M=  \left[ \begin{array}{cc}
         \Delta_1 &amp;amp; L&lt;br /&gt;
        L^T  &amp;amp; \Delta_2
     \end{array}  \right]     \label{omnibus}
$$ where $L$ is an imputed or estimated matrix for the two dissimilarities between $n$ objects. The embedding of this matrix will result in $2n$ observations of $d$-dimensional vectors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we minimize a common multidimensional scaling objective function known as raw stress to embed, the objective function can be decomposed into three terms that are interpretable.
Fidelity describes how well the embedding in commensurate space preserves the original dissimilarities ${\Delta_k},k=1,2$. These terms would be the only ones that are minimized   if we embedded the dissimilarity matrices separately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Commensurability is how well the embedding  in commensurate space preserves matchedness of matched observations. These terms correspond to the deviation from the real dissimilarities between matched observations and the distances between matched points in the embedding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Separability is how well the embedding  in commensurate space preserves the disparateness of unmatched observations.
These terms correspond to the deviation from the real dissimilarities between unmatched observations and the distances between unmatched points in the embedding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We show that a weight parameter that controls the terms&amp;rsquo; importance in the minimization of raw stress is essential for data exploitation task such as detection of new matched observations, given a set of  matched observations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joint Optimization of Fidelity and Commensurability for Manifold Alignment and Graph Matching</title>
      <link>https://adalisan.github.io/publication/thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adalisan.github.io/publication/thesis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;More detail can easily be written here using &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt; and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning spatiotemporal features for infrared action recognition with 3d convolutional neural networks</title>
      <link>https://adalisan.github.io/publication/infracv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adalisan.github.io/publication/infracv/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seeded Graph Matching Via Joint Optimization of Fidelity and Commensurability</title>
      <link>https://adalisan.github.io/publication/sgmviajofc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adalisan.github.io/publication/sgmviajofc/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manifold matching: Joint optimization of fidelity and commensurability</title>
      <link>https://adalisan.github.io/publication/manmatch-jofc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adalisan.github.io/publication/manmatch-jofc/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
